<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Community Organizations on occasional posts about technology </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/community-organizations/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>OOPSLA 2008 Around the corner.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/oopsla-2008/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/oopsla-2008/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oopsla.org/oopsla2008/&#34;&gt;OOPSLA 2008&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.sigplan.org/oopsla.htm&#34;&gt;Object-Oriented Programming, Systems, Languages, and Applications&lt;/a&gt; or more commonly referred to OOPSLA, annual conference is right around the corner. Oct 19th through the 23rd in Nashville, TN. I am trying to get my company to pay for me to go, but on such short notice, doubt it will happen, even so, I should be able to get paid time off to attend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This years conference is looking to be a great one. As always they have a ton of workshops and &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oopsla.org/oopsla2008/tutorials.html&#34;&gt;tutorials&lt;/a&gt; and the keynotes this year look decent. I am particularly interested in the &amp;ldquo;Building Service-Oriented Architectures with Web Services&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Test-Driven Hands On&amp;rdquo; tutorials. Those fall in to my line of work and I am always interested in seeing how others approach the same problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oopsla.org/oopsla2008/invited-speakers.html&#34;&gt;keynotes&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.oopsla.org/oopsla2008/invited-speakers.html&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wirfs-brock.com/&#34;&gt;Rebecca&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;What Drives Design&amp;rdquo; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mark_Jason_Dominus&#34;&gt;Mark Dominus&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; &amp;ldquo;Atypical Types&amp;rdquo; both spark my interest.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Renewing my roots.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/renewing-my-roots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/renewing-my-roots/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently renewed my ACCU and ACM memberships after letting them go for a couple years. I feel like I&amp;rsquo;ve done myself a disservice by letting these lapse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both of these organizations provided me with countless hours of information and insight as a younger developer and I attribute their journals and usergroups to helping me become the programmer I am today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These organizations promote growth and learning and both have the goal of making people do what they do better. Easier, smarter, more efficient. I think any programmer who cares about their craft and improving their abilities should seriously look at joining one or both of these organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re a past member who has let their subscription lapse it might be time to look in to renewing it, it will pay for itself many times over.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt; ACM - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.acm.org&#34;&gt;http://www.acm.org&lt;/a&gt; (a Plone site! Yes, seriously)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;ACCU - &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.accu.org&#34;&gt;http://www.accu.org&lt;/a&gt; (member count seems thin, but content is still great)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
Both give you nice print subscriptions to their journals and access to their mailing lists and discussions. ACM membership also affords you access to Books24x7 and Safari.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>