<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Project on occasional posts about technology </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/project/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays and New Server</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/holidays-new-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/holidays-new-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a little behind on my posts what with the holidays here and me doing all sorts of traveling and migrating to the new server for pieceofpy.com I haven&amp;rsquo;t really had time to make any new useful posts. So just taking the time to let everyone know I am not dead and wishing everyone happy holidays and a good winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Oh and the new server is lovely. The specs are below and so far I couldn&amp;rsquo;t be happier.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;3.2GHz P4 Core Duo2&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;2GB Memory&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;36GB 15k SCSI (Mirrored)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;500GB monthly transfer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Developing a simple insurance interface.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/eve-insurance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/eve-insurance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I play a game called &lt;a href=&#34;http://eve-online.com&#34;&gt;EVE Online&lt;/a&gt; and I create and support a lot of software for our in-game corporation. After recently migrating forums away from punBB over to vBulletin I was stuck with the choice to either migrate our existing Ship Insurance script (written in PHP) or create a whole new system from scratch. Being a lover of Python, TDD, and sausage, I of course picked the rewrite option since it would be the most difficult and suck up more resources and time than just migrating some shitty PHP script.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The requirements are very simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Allow claim to be entered.
Allow claim to be approved.
Allow a claim to be denied.
Allow an agent to see a listing of all claims.
Allow filter options by ship type and pilot.
Allow agent to enter in the payout.
Save all past claim information. (reporting)
My personal goals for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;100% coverage with unittests.
Use TDD methods to develop the project.
Use the Trac system to support development.
Use Pylons with a SQLite DB
Use Ext for any fancy shit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code available soon as I get my repository back online.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>