<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title> on occasional posts about technology </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic and static typing with unit tests.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tests-dynamic-static/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tests-dynamic-static/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an on going discussion at the office with a team member who refuses to use dynamic languages. Claiming that most of his errors are typographical errors and they are caught by the compiler. So for him, since these errors are not caught until runtime, he throws and entire group of languages out the window. He also claims that to ensure that same level of checking with a dynamic language you would have to create more unit tests than normal to prevent introducing unhandled runtime exceptions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to do a little test over the weekend. I created a very simple Number class in Python and C++. Using the exact same TDD development process, I implemented some very basic operations including division, addition, subtraction, etc&amp;hellip; I ended up with 12 tests. The exact same tests for both the C++ and Python implementation resulting in 100% of the executation path being covered. I decided that the compliation (in case of C++) and passing of the tests determined a success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then went back and inserted common typographical errors. Mistypes, extra = signs, not enough = signs, miseplled_varaibles, etc&amp;hellip; The end result was I was unable to get my unit tests passing while introducing syntax that would induce an unhandled runtime exception in Python. Granted, in C++ the compiler did catch a lot of things for me, but the point here is I didn&amp;rsquo;t have to create any extra tests to ensure that same level of confidence in my Python code.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Need a New Theme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog-need-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog-need-theme/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want a new theme for my blog. This site runs Wordpress 2.7. So please link your recommendations in the comments. I&amp;rsquo;d like something simple and clean but a little more pleasing to the eye than this current theme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been flipping through the different ones on the Wordpress site, but there is so many and I have no zero skills when it comes to what looks good and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t; I like Christmas colors if that tells you anything.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jython 2.5 and snakefight for deploying Pylons w/ SQLAlchemy &#43; Oracle.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jython-snakefight-pylons/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jython-snakefight-pylons/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;UPDATE / 13 March 2009: &lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://pypi.python.org/pypi/snakefight&#34;&gt;snakefight 0.3&lt;/a&gt; now has a &amp;ndash;include-jar option, prefer that to using my hack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://dunderboss.blogspot.com/2009/03/deploying-pylons-apps-to-java-servlet.html&#34;&gt;P. Jenvey&amp;rsquo;s blog post about Deploying Pylons Apps to Java Servlet Containers&lt;/a&gt; I immediately downloaded the Jython 2.5 beta and installed snakefight to give it a try. One of our services where I work is a Pylons based application. It is deployed using paster and Apache ProxyPass. Our main application is written in Java and is deployed as a war under Jetty. So if I can get my Pylons application built as a war and deployed that way, it would greatly simplify our deployment process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[sourcecode language=&amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo;]
$ sudo /opt/jython25/bin/easy_install snakefight
$ /opt/jython25/bin/jython setup.py develop
$ /opt/jython25/bin/jython setup.py bdist_war &amp;ndash;paster-config dev_r2.ini
&amp;hellip; output of success and stuff &amp;hellip;
$ cp dist/project-0.6.8dev.war /opt/jetty/webapps
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I visit my local server and hit the project context. I get some database errors, kind of expected them. So for the time being, I&amp;rsquo;ll be running this directly using Jython to speed up the debugging process. A quick googling of my DB issues turns up &lt;a href=&#34;http://pylonshq.com/pasties/77c3184b14d6936d86d13e4e65df92d2&#34;&gt;zxoracle for SQLalchemy&lt;/a&gt; which uses Jython zxJDBC. I install that in to sqlalchemy/databases as zxoracle.py and give it another go. Changing the oracle:// lines in my .ini file to now read zxoracle:// Now it can&amp;rsquo;t find the 3rd party Oracle libraries (ojdbc.jar).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[sourcecode]
$ cd ./dist
$ jar xf project-0.6.8dev.war
$ cd WEB-INF/lib
$ ls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;no ojdbc.jar as expected &amp;hellip;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$ cd ~/project
$ export CLASSPATH=/opt/jython25/jython.jar:/usr/lib/jvm/java/jre/lib/ext/ojdbc.jar
$ /opt/jython25/bin/jython /opt/jython25/bin/paster serve &amp;ndash;reload dev_r2.ini
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now it is looking a little better and it able to find the jar, but still a DB issue, now with SQLalchemy library. Not having a ton of time to investigate, I decide to try rolling back my SQAlachemy version for Jython. Turns out rolling back to 0.5.0 fixed the issue. I&amp;rsquo;ll be investigating why it was breaking with 0.5.2 soon &amp;trade;. So now I rerun it, and get a new error.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[sourcecode lang=&amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo;]
AttributeError: &amp;lsquo;ZXOracleDialect&amp;rsquo; object has no attribute &amp;lsquo;optimize_limits&amp;rsquo;
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decide I am just going to go in to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://trac.pieceofpy.com/pieceofpy/browser/snakefight-java-libs&#34;&gt;zxoracle.py and add optimize_limits = False to the ZXOracleDialect&lt;/a&gt;. No idea what this breaks or harms, but I do it anyway and rerun the application. Success! Every thing is working now. No liking the idea of having to manually insert the Oracle jar in to the WEB-INF/lib and not really wanting to much around with environment variables, I also implemented a quick and dirty include-java-libs for snakefight, the diff for command.py is below. This allows me to pass in a : separated list of jars to include in the WEB-INF/lib. &lt;strong&gt;EDIT: &lt;/strong&gt;The diff I posted isn&amp;rsquo;t needed since I put it on my hg repo. &lt;a href=&#34;http://trac.pieceofpy.com/pieceofpy/browser/snakefight-java-libs&#34;&gt;You can grab it from here.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So now I am back to building my war. Just as before.
[sourcecode lang=&amp;ldquo;bash&amp;rdquo;]
$ /opt/jython25/bin/jython setup.py bdist_war &amp;ndash;paste-config dev_r2.ini &amp;ndash;include-java-libs /opt/jython25/extlibs/ojdbc.jar
running bdist_war
creating build/bdist.java1.6.0_12
creating build/bdist.java1.6.0_12/war
creating build/bdist.java1.6.0_12/war/WEB-INF
creating build/bdist.java1.6.0_12/war/WEB-INF/lib-python
running easy_install project
adding eggs (to WEB-INF/lib-python)
adding jars (to WEB-INF/lib)
adding WEB-INF/lib/jython.jar
adding Paste ini file (to dev_r2.ini)
adding Paste app loader (to WEB-INF/lib-python/____loadapp.py)
generating deployment descriptor
adding deployment descriptor (WEB-INF/web.xml)
created dist/project-0.6.8dev-py2.5.war
$ cp dist/project-0.6.8dev-py2.5.war /opt/jetty/webapps
$ sudo /sbin/service jetty restart
[/sourcecode]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And presto! I am in business. My pylons application is deployed under Jetty and all the &lt;a href=&#34;http://seleniumhq.org/&#34;&gt;selenium functional tests&lt;/a&gt; are passing. I am sure there is probably a easier, neater, or cleaner way to do all this, but this was my first iteration through and also my first time ever deploying a WAR to a java servlet container so all in all I am happy with the results. Performance seems about the same as when running the application with paster serve, but Jetty does use a little more memory than before (expected I guess).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Migrating to Blogofile</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/migration-blogofile/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/migration-blogofile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Because I am a lemming and everyone else is doing it, I too am going to migrate to blogofile! Then I&amp;rsquo;ll blog about doing it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Moving by blog back!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/moving-blog-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/moving-blog-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;ok, combining personal blog and tech blog was a bad idea. I didn&amp;rsquo;t realize there were some many people following each that were completely uninsterested in the other one. So after some thought, I will be bring back all my Tech posting to &lt;a href=&#34;http://pieceofpy.com&#34;&gt;pieceofpy.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My personal stuff will now be on &lt;a href=&#34;http://riotousliving.com&#34;&gt;Riotous Living&lt;/a&gt;! which is a much better platform for all the crazy stuff I do that isn&amp;rsquo;t tech related.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks for putting up with all my shifting and moving around!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Software Analogy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-software-analogy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-software-analogy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-full wp-image-303&#34; title=&#34;unrelated-picture&#34; src=&#34;http://pieceofpy.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/unrelated-picture.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;unrelated-picture&#34; width=&#34;450&#34; height=&#34;360&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometimes putting into words the practices you use can expose obvious flaws where you needimprovementsand provide a starting point for introducing new practices in to your development. Analogies are often used to express sometimes foreign, sometimes complex ideas by bringing them in to a realm that is familiar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Idea&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;My development is fueled with an idea. The idea sometimes bad, sometimes good, and rarely great, but nonetheless this is where I start. The idea usually stems from a problem. I want to be able to do Foo or I&amp;rsquo;d really like if Bar was able to do this.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;What ever it maybe, I think it is important to take the time to outline your idea. Give yourself some initial requirements. Give yourself some structure to build on. You need a solid foundation for a project to be seen to completion and even with that, most fail to make it.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;Now don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, I am not saying you need a full set of business requirements with risk analysis, input from legal, hiring a marketing firm to ensure there issufficientmarket share to capture to justify the risk of development. I am just saying you need to have some kind of outline, some set of initial requirements, your motivation. They are easy to create and it only takes a minute.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once it makes it past the idea stage, it means I&amp;rsquo;ve written down on paper. I&amp;rsquo;ve created a loose set of requirements for the project and I still think it is a decent enough idea to continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Design&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;The design process is unique beast. There is plenty of reading material out there about design and about architecting software. I am by no means a great architect. I know enough UML to not be confused by it, but I couldn&amp;rsquo;t punch my way out of a wet Visio box.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My approach to design is brief at best. I hop a plane to 30,000 ft and look around. I make some notes of that obvious things I see. Oh look a Factory Pattern, oh look a white fluffy Strategy pattern, hey that skyscrapper looks a lot like a Reactor pattern and that lake looks like a Facade. I like patterns, even though some people seem to think they hinder innovation and developers coming up with new awesomeness. I make some notes and polish my lead balls to ensure my development compass points North. That is it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a rule of thumb, I try to spend no more than a day on this phase. Depending on the scope of the project and the requirements you may require more or less time, but that is really up to your gut. As soon as you feel comfortable laying down code, start laying down code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&#34;aligncenter size-medium wp-image-302&#34; title=&#34;plants-tell-me-fings&#34; src=&#34;http://pieceofpy.com/wp-content/uploads/2009/04/plants-tell-me-fings-300x225.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;plants-tell-me-fings&#34; width=&#34;300&#34; height=&#34;225&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Now The Analogy -GrowingSoftware.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;span style=&#34;font-weight: normal;&#34;&gt;I am a giant fan boi when it comes to test driven and agile processes, I mix and match the different processes to meet my needs. My favorite anology I use to describe my process of what I like to call organic development, involves growing plants. I am sure the term organic development already exists and means something completely different, but I don&amp;rsquo;t care, I like it for this.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Idea - Decide you want to plant something and read up on what you&amp;rsquo;re planting.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Design - Sun? Shade? Raised bed?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Coding - Watering,fertilizing, repotting and transplanting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
So with the idea you read about what you are planting. You look at maybe some other people who have planted the same type of plants and read on their experiences if they are available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now the design. You pick out your pots or bed type. Decide if you are gonna usenaturallight,artificiallight, how much water and they type of delivery mechanism? I hear they have these cool water globes now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can plant the seed. You water and weed and as your plantgrowsyou prune, stake in supports, and continue to care for it until it comes to bare.With the proper care and handling you can produce a healthy, beautiful, lowmaintenanceplant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keeping with this software is a plant analogy, somethings to watch out for. Water too much you run the risk of killing your plant (developer burn out). Prune too much and you can kill it (premature optimization). Basically in the early stages of a plants life mistakes can easily kill it I think this is very similar to software.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As your plant takes root it becomes easier and easier to maintain. Things like transplanting, ripping a plant out to the roots andreplantingin a new bed are risky, but if done right, can produce a larger, healthier plant. Like software, sometimes completely gutting a prototype might be the right thing to do, but you increase the risk of killing the project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But also plants, like software, can be very forgiving as long as you catch the the fact early that you are giving your plant too much or too little of water, pruning, fertilizer, soil to grow in, etc&amp;hellip; you should be able tosalvageit. Though it will take more work and time, with extended care an over or under watered plant can be saved from the brink of death with a little time investment and care. But sometimes there is nothing you can do, like an over pruned Bonsaitree, once the damage is done, even if you continue to grow your plant, it will never feel right for many many years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So anyway, that is might crazy, abrupt, all over the place abstract take on software. What&amp;rsquo;s yours?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a side note, an email commenter Linda requested I have more pictures in my posts so this one is for you Linda.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;EDIT: Fixed the strong tags. WP decided to do something weird with the formatting. Also fixed some typo&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I Look For In A Job</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/job-hunting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/job-hunting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;m currently looking for new work and I&amp;rsquo;ve defined my list of items that are high priority to me. I figured I&amp;rsquo;d list them here and then break each down in to a little detail. Mainly because I&amp;rsquo;m up late at a stopping point in some code and haven&amp;rsquo;t updated my blog in forever.
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Refreshing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Excitement&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Vision&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Caring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Refreshing&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do I mean by refreshing? I mean a company that isn&amp;rsquo;t doing what everyone else. Something that isn&amp;rsquo;t YAIC (Yet Another Internet Company). For me, this can really mean two things though. It could also mean a company that produces software for an industry I&amp;rsquo;ve never worked in before, but ideally it is a company doing something new, innovative, and refreshing. At the end of the day, writing software for them makes you go &amp;ldquo;Ahhhhhhhhhh&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Excitement&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I want everyone in the company I am working for to be jacked about working there. I want people to be excited about the products. Even if they are boring everyday products. If everyone there is excited about them and cares about them it promotes a much better work environment and in my experience a higher quality product.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vision&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s where we are. Here&amp;rsquo;s where we are going. Here is how WE are gonna do it. This seems as one of those things that is so easily over looked once you&amp;rsquo;re out of lets keep this startup from dying working 100 hours a week mode, but even for established companies this is so important. Without a vision your company will eventually end up stuck in the mud.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Caring&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is more in the human respect. We are sometimes at work more than we are at home. This is especially the case with small companies and start-ups (and even some big ones). Companies that care, have employees that care. Treating employees like cattle will only result in employees treating the company like a feed station. Every place I&amp;rsquo;ve worked that did mandatory start / end times or mandatory OT always had issues getting coverage and had huge turn over rates compared to flex time locations with resources for employees to relax, take breaks, and feel cared about.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>jQuery getJSON and IE cache</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/jquery-getjson-ie-cache/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/jquery-getjson-ie-cache/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am sure everyone else who lives in the world of jQuery knows this, so this is more here for my own future reference and avoiding and more wasting of time, but if you are going to us $.getJSON helper in jQuery, append a time stamp to it to prevent odd caching behavior in IE. See the example below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;
$.getJSON(&amp;ldquo;/story/story&lt;em&gt;id.php?&lt;/em&gt;=&amp;ldquo;+(new Date().getTime()), function(json) {
    $(&amp;lsquo;#next_story_id&amp;rsquo;).html(&amp;rsquo;S&amp;rsquo; + json.next_story_id);
});
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This might not be the best way to do it and really, this is good practice for all dynamic requests to avoid caching issues from the browser and the server. Chalk this up as a good learning experience that sucked 30 minutes of my life. I hate front end stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>paster shell - do people know about it?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/pylons-paster-shell/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/pylons-paster-shell/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I was having a chat today about Pylons vs. Django and for the most part it was pretty diplomatic. We got to talking about the Admin interface the Django has. Which you don&amp;rsquo;t have to do any extra boiler plate for, it is just there for you. With Pylons you have to use something like FormAlchemy or use Turbogears to get a similar style admin interface for your models and data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since we were sitting at a computer, I went ahead brought up a quick project and did a little demo of the paster shell. Sure, it involves typing and it isn&amp;rsquo;t as pretty or &amp;ldquo;fast&amp;rdquo; as an admin panel, but he didn&amp;rsquo;t even know it existed. One of the common things he mentioned was, &amp;ldquo;if I want to change the menus that are dynamically defined&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;if a username needs to be changed&amp;rdquo; .. and the application itself doesn&amp;rsquo;t have a custom admin panel, with Pylons he had to do raw SQL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;
$paster shell pylons_config.ini

All objects from demo.lib.base are available
Additional Objects:
   mapper     -  Routes mapper object
   wsgiapp    -  This project&#39;s WSGI App instance
   app        -  paste.fixture wrapped around wsgiapp

&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; error_user = meta.Session.query(model.User).filter_by(username=&#39;wwitzel 3&#39;).one()
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; # nice thing about this, is you also will get exceptions throw if more than one record exists
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; error_user.username
u&#39;wwitzel 3&#39;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; error_user.username = &#39;wwitzel3&#39;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; meta.Session.commit()
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; menu_typo = meta.Session.query(model.Menu).filter_by(id=1).one()
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; menu_typo.value
u&#39;Abuot&#39;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; menu_typo.value = &#39;About&#39;
&amp;gt;&amp;gt;&amp;gt; meta.Session.commit()
&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So that is a very simple example of how one would use the paster shell to update some bad data in the database while ensuring integrity of your custom model and extension code. After I showed this to my friend he wasn&amp;rsquo;t as concerned about the lack of a web interface for administration within Pylons.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>