<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Python Personal on occasional posts about technology </title>
      <generator uri="https://gohugo.io">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/python-personal/index.xml</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exercise even a programmer can do.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/programmers-exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/programmers-exercise/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I&amp;rsquo;ve been exercising lately. The last visit to the Dr. was a wake up call. 300 lb .. WHAT?! So, taking an iterative approach to exercise, I&amp;rsquo;ve manged to work up to 6-day a week cardio routine and a 3-day a week strength training routine and have gone from just over 300 lb. to 270 lb. in a couple months. Couple friends asked how I started and what I do, so I figure I&amp;rsquo;d break it down here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started by walking. 3 times a week for a couple weeks. Then after reading a Lifehacker post about a morning routine and matabolism, I added my very fast morning routine and actually eating breakfast to my day. Made it a whole week Monday-Friday. Then I bumped up the walking to Monday through Saturday. Did the morning routine and the walking for another week, then I bumped up the walking to targeted cardio 3 out of the 6 days and did that for another week. Added strength training 1 out of the 6 days and did that for another week. Switched from walking to cardio on all 6 days and + 1 more week. Then strength training 3 days out of the week. And slowly over about 3 months, I built up to this routine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Every morning&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;i&gt;I do this right after eating breakfast&lt;/i&gt;
2 sets, push-ups, 30 sec OR failure
2 sets, scissor kicks, 1 minute OR failure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monday through Saturday&lt;/strong&gt;
2 minute warm up
20 minutes of cardio (140-160 heart rate, check with your Dr.)
2 minute cool down&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Strength training&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;i&gt;This adds another 20 minutes to my workout, so schedule for that&lt;/i&gt;
Monday - Push (chest, triceps)
Wednesday - Pull (bicep, shoulders)
Friday - Legs (legs and stomach)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, it is just habit. Also, I am sure there is some study somewhere to prove or disprove this, but I find it makes my mind much sharper. I am more alert through out the day and I sleep much better at night. Not to mention clothes fitting better and just feeling better. My personal goal is 250.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Python tip&lt;/strong&gt;
Prefer xrange to range when you need an arbitrary number of iterations as range actually generates a list for you, this will consume memory and be more costly than xrange.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>